Sufyan Saleem

Address: Phase 6, Sector F8, Street 4, House 425, Hayatabad, Peshawar Email: sufyansalim94@gmail.com

Mobile: +923139243550

OBJECTIVE

I am a 24 years old Software Engineer who loves to play with different technologies. I am looking forward for a promising technical job where I will be subjected to new developmental areas with friendly environment for learning and emerging of my own personality with professional and in time work.

WORK EXPERIENCE

	WORK EXI ERIENGE		
<u>Linknbit</u>	Software Engineer	Islamabad Pakistan	
Jan 2019 – present	Working for Software Development and IT Sol Agency. My main roles include developing We Applications and Hybrid Mobile Applications.	utions	
Jan 2019 – present	Global Aviation System	I am working on parts of backend Node JS, Express, Swagger, Sequelize cli & Azure SQL	
	 Dynasty Unleashed Models Modeling agency App for Fashion designers and marketers Users can register, create profile, add people and hire models at will 	Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native & part of Deployment to Firebase & Google Play	
	 Ecommerce Mobile App. User can register, select products, add products to cart. User add products to wish list and checkout. Project was abandoned on last stage due to funds not provided and outsourced to someone else. My Version 	React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Node JS, Rest API, Word Press API, Woo Commerce API, Native Base	
	 Yogurt App Step-by-step guide to home crafted authentic Yogurt and Kefir. Take the directions on your phone. Make Yogurt and Kefir at home and communicate. 	Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native, Expo, Native Base	
	<u>SmartsAid</u>	React/React-Native, Expo,	

NGO App for refuges

Redux, Firebase, Rest API,

React Native Elements

2018 - FYP Currency Recognition & Conversion Android, Java, Open CV, Rest API, MATLAB Developed an app where users can scan currency note and it will tell which currency it is and how much is it and show the exchange rate in USD. 2014 - 2018 Content Management Systems Java, C#, MSSQL Gym - Point of Sale PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL 2010 RuneScape RPG Java Created bot script for the game called RuneScape. The bot played the game for you. Portfolio Projects DevCamper API HTML, NodeJS, Express, Mongoose,

Bootcamps API

One can register as a User or Publisher and login also.

Publisher can create Bootcamps.

- Admin and Publisher can add courses and perform various CRUD operations.
- Users can comment on Bootcamps and update their profile, add picture, and reset password.

DevConnector

- Social Media for developers where users register.
- Create profile, create posts, add comments and like and unlike them.

React, Redux, CSS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, NodeJS, Heroku

MongoDB, Node mailer,

Injection

Security for XSS and NOSQL

SmartBrain

- Smart Brain an app with face Recognition.
- Users can register, login and submit images via URL.
- The AI recognizes the face in the picture and draw a border around.
- It works only for one face in the image.

React, Redux, CSS, PostgreSQL, Knex, Express, Nodejs, Heroku, Netlify

EDUCATION

Internet of things and AI Specialist Course

PIAIC, Islamabad (2019 - present)

BS in Software Engineering, cgpa 2.78

Institute of Managements Sciences, Peshawar (2014 – 2018)

F.Sc - Pre-Engineering, grade B

ICMS College System Peshawar (2012 – 2014)

Racines School System, Peshawar (2010 – 2012)

SPECIALITY AND KNOWLEDGE

Specialities

Mobile/Hybrid App Developer Web Developer

Social Links









Knowledge

React/React-Native, Redux, Expo JS, Node JS, Express Mongoose, Sequelize Firebase, Mongo DB HTML, CSS, Bootstrap Git, Heroku Rust

Word press, Android Studio, Adobe PS

LANGUAGES AND HOBBIES

Languages

English Urdu Pashto

Hobbies

Programming, Music, Movies, Video Games, Reading, Hiking, Bodybuilding,